tanvi mehta

What do you get when you mix graphic design, human interest, and painstaking meticulousness?

A design practitioner who creates experiences through visuals.

Through my work in graphic design, I explore the impact of visual cues on human behaviour, and by extension, user experience. An eye for detail and scrupulous planning are strengths I bring to the table, along with a big heart and lots of tea sachets.

Birthdate: 06/06/1997

Contact: +91 9619682684

Email Id: tanvimehta6697@gmail.com

Address: 3, Deepak, 401, S.V.Road, Vile Parle (West), Mumbai- 400056, Maharashtra, India.

Website: www.inkyesthetics.com

Instagram account: @inkyesthetics

Languages: English, Gujrati, Hindi, Marathi

Technical Skills: Software: Photoshop, Illustrator I, Indesign, Flash, Fireworks, Adobe XD.

Hobbies: Photography, Dancing, Hiking, Sketching, Painting, Travelling, Theatre.

Extra - Curricular Activities:

- Completed a 6 week long course on 'Visual Elements of User Interface Design' offered by California Institute of Arts in July 2020 from Coursera.
- Volunteered in an event at RMZ Ecoworld, Bangalore in 2018 and presented a project 'Lakere' based on the Lakes in Bangalore telling a story about how they have dried or been misused with aim to create awareness about them.
- Founder of a brand 'MOH' and set-up a stall for it as a volunteer at Sunday Soul Sante, Bangalore, in 2017. Produced sustainable and decorated pocket perfume bottles by reusing waste nail polish bottles..
- Volunteered at Serendipity Art Festival, Panjim, Goa in 2017. Oversaw the logo designing, branding, and advertising for the 15 installations for Srishti School of Art Design and Technology.
- Represented India for folk dance at the Kocaeli Büyükşehir Belediyesi in Turkey in 2015.
- Volunteered at 'Anant Vikas' an NGO that focuses on inclusive rural development, Ashte Village, 2015. Taught children Math and Science, Educated villagers the importance of healthcare and provided them required supplies.

Education:

Parsons School of Design | The New School //

New York, United States of America // 2021 - Present

Currently pursuing Master of Science in Strategic Design and Management Recipient: Dean's Merit based scholarship

Srishti Institute of Art Design and Technology // Bangalore, India // 2015 - 2019

Secured a Bachelor of Design in Visual Communication and Strategic Branding.

Experience:

The Glitch, Flux // Graphic Designer

Mumbai, India

March 2020 - June 2021

The Glitch, W.P.P is India's leading creative agency headquartered in Mumbai, with offices in Delhi and Bangalore.

- Worked on campaign ideas and build visual style guides for brands such as Netflix, Dell, One Plus, BoAt, Cred, Moms and Co, Diageo, etc.
- Led the design team international campaign for Dell during the pandemic.
- Designed graphics for various advertising videos for Instagram TV, YouTube and LinkedIn for brands such as Netflix, Dell, BoAt, Moms and Co, Diageo, etc.
- Worked on pitches for brands such as Pepsi, Bumble, Pepperfry, Cred, etc.

Hepta // UX/UI Designer & Brand Visualiser

Mumbai, India

August 2019 - February 2020

The Hepta is a UI/UX and Technology agency, serving the startups and businesses to achieve strategic objectives by delivering impactful UI/UX and technology services.

- Ideated and designed e-commerce and charity websites on Photoshop with a cross-functional team inclusive of stakeholders, project managers and developers to create responsive interfaces and a user-centered experience.
- Curated logos, brand guidelines and packaging designs to help upcoming brands gain recognition

Rivet Design Studio // Environmental Graphics Intern

Bangalore, India

April 2019 - July 2019

Rivet Design is a communication and design studio, which works on environmental graphics, branding and various ways of communication through design.

 Worked from ideation to execution and designed the environmental graphics for the Amazon Campus in Hyderabad.

Yes Yes Why Not // Graphic Design & UX/UI Design Intern Mumbai, India // April 2018 - July 2018

Agratha Academy - Soundwaves // Graphic Designer Mumbai, India // May 2017 - June 2017

Barworld India // Illustrator & Graphic Designer Freelance Mumbai, India // May 2017 - Present

Zcyphher Studio // Graphic Design Intern Mumbai, India // May 2016 - July 2016

Cat Café Studio // Graphic Design Intern Mumbai, India // May 2016 - July 2016

Projects:

Ampmatuer // Designed an 'Ampmatr' application for amateur musicians to learn, create, discover and share their music.

- Conducted primary and secondary research, performed field experiments and insight generation, as well as executed early ideation analysis and prototyping to find a holistic learning experience for amateur musicians
- Performed extensive research to understand basic skills and to get exposure to new music and other artists.
- Technologies used: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign

Creative Collaborations // Worked in a 'Creative Collaboration' project in Kutch with a Rabari artisan and built a system to bridge the communication gap between her and the target audience.

- Performed primary and secondary research, conducted field experiments and insight generation, and executed early ideation analysis and prototyping for creating a tool to reduce the communication gap between the artisan and her audience.
- Technologies used: Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign.